hey everyone thanks for listening to the
grow your life podcast my name is
jeremiah krakowski if you haven't heard
this podcast before
i've been helping trainers and coaches
for the last 19 years grow their
businesses
scale to eight figures and get more
clients and customers and they know what
to do with to build the business of
their dreams now even if you're just
getting started even if you're at zero
these principles apply
we've used these principles to take
people from zero
brand new getting started
to being successful seven and eight
figure business owners
and so don't think that oh i'm not at
that level or oh i'm not trying to get
to that level
my friends no matter what
goal you have
this podcast has the blueprint for you
if you're a coach
trainer course grader now today
it's going to be a little bit
ranty
uh
a little more unfiltered
a little more on edge and i'm not gonna
beat around the bush at all okay
now what i would like to do is i would i
would encourage you
to try to listen to the whole episode
all the way through
i know a lot of people i can see the
stats you listen
and you dip off about halfway through if
you do come back and listen to the rest
of it because this is going to be i
think one of the most important episodes
that i've ever done
and something that i think is very
very important listen if you're a coach
or a trainer and you want to make money
in a business right
you have to do
the work
the right work the work that produces
results
if you haven't made progress in the last
30 days
to where your situation is different
in a positive way than it was 30 days
ago
something has to change and the
activities that you're doing on a daily
basis
weekly basis
are not the correct activities
and that's a harsh statement but it's
very true
because
the speed of how the internet moves
how stuff happens
you can't sit around
and
wait for things to happen my friends
you just can't
you can't sit around and wait for a
situation to change
even if it just means taking 30 minutes
a day
to build your business that's 15 hours a
month
i think everybody could actually find 30
minutes a day
no matter what their life situation is
who's listening to this and those who
have more time
you could spend at least
40 to 60 hours a month
building your business recording a
course
creating your offers
launching campaigns marketing getting
stuff out there i want you to look at
what are the projects in front of you
why haven't you done them yet
why have you not
done the next step
get real honest and answer that question
and most of the time it has to do with
fear and worry of not being able to
handle what would happen when you did
finish that because
otherwise you would have gotten it done
already it's usually always fear and
worry okay
so
take a look at
and evaluate
every step of the way every month
every couple months what am i afraid of
that's stopping me from going to the
next level
what is stopping me from doing the
things that i know that i need to do
what is stopping me from building the
business of my dreams
what is stopping me from progressing
and increasing my income by 200
in the next
three months
i'm serious i'm so serious here
see
i have clients
fortunately
their previous clients but i look
and they
literally haven't done anything
different than they did five years ago
and i still see them struggling and i
asked them they're like i'm doing good
i'm doing good i'm doing my friends
like it's a it's a mental
illness at that point
to keep
thinking that your situation is going to
change
by operating in the same pattern that
hasn't produced results it's called
insanity
something has to change
just one thing can have a huge impact
now i get it some of us are like well
i'm waiting for something to change like
maybe you're waiting for a for a
non-compete contract to come up because
you legally can't build your business
okay i get that example right
that's not most of your situations
oh i'm waiting for my divorce to go
through okay i get it
but that's not most of your situations
i'm waiting for
my
my kids to go back to school
stop using your kids as an excuse
seriously i get it that they take time
and i know that just by saying that i
probably just offended
a good portion of you
my mom built her business with all of us
as kids and we didn't feel neglected
when she built a business and i know
plenty of parents that make it work
and their kids don't feel neglected
because they
know what their priorities are
they don't make excuses they don't come
up with a thousand and one reasons why
they can't
they get to bed on time they take care
of their health
they watch what they eat they watch what
they consume on social media they watch
what they consume on television
my friends some of you are addicted
to sugar
pornography
the news
social media
and you're in denial about it and you'd
like to change it
and that addiction is actually what's
stopping you from building your business
what i've actually found is a pattern of
is a lot of people
are not doing what they want because
they're not trusting themselves to do
what they want to in an area of
addiction and if that's the case
work through that
whatever you need to do
to work through that to break that
addiction could be cigarettes could be
something else like that
i get it i i
have had an addictive personality i and
and i've had stuff in my life that i've
had to
break free from
and they were stopping me a year ago i
struggled massively uh with sugar it was
a big one i was eating sugar all the
time
like and couldn't figure out why i
couldn't focus and get stuff done
went on a detox worked on that was
intentional to stop making excuses
for why i couldn't
and figured out how i can see too often
we come up with reasons why
we can't and then we end up believing
the big fat lies
that we tell ourselves
your business
requires
speed
of you
not sitting around hoping something
changes it requires speed
in the big picture stuff takes a long
time so you better shorten up
how long it takes you to make decisions
to jump on something i see people take
six to 12 months to make one decision
in their business
that they should have made 500 decisions
in that time
you will never be successful if that's
you
until you change that behavior
if you're
constantly going based off of what you
feel
i don't feel like building my business
today you will never be successful
until you change that
oh i just i got too much going on
keep making excuses you will never be
successful
until you figure out how to stop making
those excuses and and and the truth is
it's impossible to
i'm not talking about hustle grind
burnout
either
i'm talking about
taking care of yourself
taking care of your family and creating
the life that you've always wanted
when are you going to get over your
excuses
when are you going to get past
the reasons why
you've convinced yourself that you can't
build a business
right now
today
oh the big one
jeremiah that's easy for you to say you
got money plus you had a a mom who was
successful right you don't know my
situation i'm not you
okay
and
go make some money
go
save some money
stop coming up with bs reasons
why you can't succeed
because of whatever lies you've told
yourself over the years
whatever those excuse what what's the
reason that's bubbling up inside of you
right now
i'd love for you to share it with me i'd
love for you to dive deep into whatever
that is
google it
here's something that i do when i
identify an excuse and a reason that i
can't break past
i actually open up google
and ask google
the solution to my problem okay so like
for instance um how to build a business
and you don't have
money to do so
creative ways to start without money how
to start when you don't have money how
to start when you literally have no
money
and there's articles all over google
that can answer some of those questions
or
how to manage your time to build a
business
with kids
get a schedule put your kids on a
schedule maintain flexibility see what
the truth is the reason why you can't
isn't usually the reason why you can't
the reason why is maybe you you
literally are incapable of cutting out
the time wasters maybe you're incapable
of leading your kids to be on a schedule
or yourself maybe you're incapable of
getting help
because you
are bad at communication whatever that
is
whatever reasons that you have there's
usually a layer deep
of what the real reason is it's a lot
deeper than just the surface level crap
that we
pair it out that we've invented in our
brain as to why we can't
like my number one reason still to this
day that i give for why my business is
where it's at and not where i want it to
be
is that i don't have enough time
and i and i need more money to hire more
people okay so i'm doing something to
solve that
i'm doing something to solve that
get up earlier
go to bed earlier manage time
cancel certain commitments
sell some things
learn to budget better
take on some extra side things like that
see that's what i'm saying my friends
whatever reason that you have given
yourself you have to attack
you can't just sit there and coddle it
like a cute little baby and hope it
grows up one day and leaves the house
what are your reasons what are your
sacred cows what are the reasons that
you think
you you can't change
what situations are too big
for you
to build your business
what excuses have you given yourself
go after them identify them
shine a bright light on them
and watch your life change
too many people are living in
just
making love with their excuses
they will never succeed
until they change that habit
okay
and the truth is when you identify your
excuses you can then start to make a
plan
to not let them defeat you
start to get a vision for the future
what if what if just magically imagine
in your brain you waved a magic wand and
your excuses were gone and some of you
that terrifies you because you're like i
don't want to wave a magic wand in my
brain and my kids disappear
why are you so afraid to even let your
brain go there
brain think about certain things that
you won't even go through the mental
thought process of it
step out and take that risk
the mental thought process oh i don't
know how to do something here's another
great excuse i don't know how to do it
great
ask some people who do
well i'm embarrassed they won't want to
help me oh that's the real reason you're
embarrassed see the real reason that
most people don't build their business
is they care about too much how they
look to everybody else
what everybody else thinks about them
and being perfect little
perfect person
to everybody
that they're afraid of ever going
outside the boundaries of what perfect
person would do
that they please everybody that they're
not authentic to who they really are
because they're afraid of not being
the perfect little version of themselves
that they think they have to be to make
everybody in their life happy to manage
and maintain and control
other people's responses see that's the
real issue
that's the real reason why most people
actually don't get the help they need to
build their business
pride
people pleasing
and the need to control other people
and the need to
be so perfect all the time that it never
upsets anybody
that root
will keep you broke
forever
until you change it
see we have to get real clear and start
to identify
what are the reasons why
i'm not moving things forward in my
business
your business requires
speed
sitting around for months
letting these issues run your life like
a slave master
whipping you into shape of failure
is the life that you have chosen to live
right now because you're not doing
anything different
or
you can choose something different
imagine that you waved a magic wand all
those things were gone what would your
life look like
and for some of you that's impossible to
see that vision because there's too many
layers of things to remove when you
remove one and another one comes up
that's the hard part of building a
business my friends
that's the hardest part
of building a business
is removing those layers
to identify what's actually holding you
back
and most people
don't have the capacity ability will
tenacity and commitment to
ever
walk that path and that's most of the
people even who listen to this podcast
they never will
you
probably never will
because you've chosen not to
or you can choose
differently
starting today not tomorrow
when some magic fairy tale situation
changes
today
what are you waiting for
what excuse have you come up with what
what new
reason
have you given yourself for why you
can't see at this point there is none
and we start to realize wow
maybe i'm the one that's responsible
for why my life is where it's at right
now taking personal responsibility is
one of the number one things that you
can do
to change your life
now there's three books that i really
highly recommend on this topic
extreme ownership by jocko willink
all about personal responsibility
the big leap
by gay hendricks
conquer your hidden fear
and take your life to the next level
and then how to do
the
work by nicole lepra
these three books
are foundational at identifying why
those patterns are there
breaking free from them breaking past
the fears and taking complete ownership
of your life to change your life
the choice
is yours
nobody else's there's nobody else to
blame in your life for why it is going
the way it is and it's not where you
want it to be
what are you going to choose today my
friends
i would hope that you would choose the
dream life that's possible for you if
you're a coach if you're a trainer if
you're somebody that is wanting to make
a difference that wants to make an
income for yourself
choosing
to create the life that you want
and putting action behind those choices
actually doing what you've chosen not
just thinking about it see i see a lot
of people that get addicted to thinking
and learning and do nothing about what
they've learned they are addicted
to feeling like they've done something
it's a lot of people who listen to this
podcast unfortunately
and they will never do anything with
what i teach even though they've
listened to every episode
because they've chosen not to
what are you going to choose today my
friends
i'd recommend choosing
to come up with a vision for your life
and start to
build out a plan and
take action on those dreams and start to
change your situation so that your life
is different
90 days from now
i believe it's possible
i believe you can do that
but most of you never will
because you're incapable of making those
choices
because you've never done it before
and there's and there's no there's
nothing i can do to change that
there's nothing anybody else in the
world can do
it's a decision and a desire in yourself
and when you can increase your level of
desire
you can take action
better
what motivates you to take action see
motivation is fleeting but discipline
creates results
doing it when you don't feel like it
produces results
what are you going to choose my friends
to let your feelings run your life to
let your past run your life
to let your your current situation of
crap
be your forever story
it's a choice many people choose that
because they're incapable of getting out
of it and and and even when somebody
shows them how they refuse to do
anything i
i gave you these three books
literally gave you these three books
they they will they will
change
at least
one part of your life if you read
through through them i'm serious
like and really absorb the content but
some of you will never even crack open
the cover of one or listen to the
audible version of even one of them
because for whatever reason
you
feel better about see a lot of people
are addicted to potential
this is a big one
i heard this on a disney plus
thing
that
a lot of people are they actually have
an addiction to not opening the box on
things
to not to to knowing that there's
information out there that they don't
know
and addicted to knowing that it exists
but not actually
using it or applying it because they're
addicted to the potential of something
changing in their life
[Music]
that's a choice to stay addicted to the
potential
and it's a choice to move past that and
realize hmm maybe i should consume
some of what i've purchased maybe i
should start doing something with what
i've learned
comes by taking action
start moving
forward instead of sitting around
hoping that someday you feel good enough
to do it
i believe in you and i know that you can
do this enjoy your life everybody we'll
talk soon